inq.com 2017-06-16

# TouchCommerce Privacy Policy

Last updated: 2017-03-14

TouchCommerce (now part of Nuance, Communications) participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. and the Swiss-US Privacy Shield Framework. TouchCommerce is committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries and Switzerland, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield List. [<https://www.privacyshield.gov/list>] 

TouchCommerce is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under the Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. TouchCommerce complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU and Switzerland, including the onward transfer liability provisions. 

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, TouchCommerce is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, TouchCommerce may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. 

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) athttps://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request.  

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website [<https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint>], you may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.  

Scope    
This Privacy Policy only addresses our use and disclosure of information we collect from you on our website[www.touchcommerce.com](http://www.touchcommerce.com/) and our service platform owned and operated by TouchCommerce (collectively, “We”, “Us”, “Our”). This Privacy Statement describes how TouchCommerce collects and uses the personal information you provide. It also describes the choices available to you regarding the use of, your access to, and how to update and correct your personal information. The data collected by the "end user" through our platform is owned by our "Client". We own all data collected on our corporate website, [www.touchcommerce.com](http://www.touchcommerce.com/). 

1\. 

TouchCommerce™ is committed to protecting your privacy. This Privacy Statement sets forth our current privacy practices with regard to the information we collect when you or your computer interact with our website. By accessing this website, you acknowledge and fully understand this Privacy Statement and freely consent to the information collection and use practices described in this Web site Privacy Statement. 

2\. 

Related services and offerings with links from this website, including vendor sites, have their own privacy statements that can be viewed by clicking on the corresponding links within each respective website. Since we do not have direct control over the policies or practices of participating merchants and other third parties, we are not responsible for the privacy practices or contents of those sites. We recommend that you always review the privacy policies of merchants and other third parties before you provide any personal information or complete any transaction with such parties. 

3\. 

TouchCommerce collects certain information from and about its users three ways: directly from our web server logs, the user, and with cookies.  **a. Web Server Logs**

When you visit our website, we may track information to administer the site and analyze its usage. Examples of information we may track include: 

  * Your Internet protocol address. 
  * The kind of browser or computer you use. 
  * Number of links you click within the site. 
  * State or country from which you accessed the site. 
  * Date and time of your visit. 
  * Name of your Internet service provider. 
  * Web page you linked to our site from. 
  * Pages you viewed on the site. 
  * We also use third-party services, such as Google Analytics, to collect and analyze such information. 

We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you. We do this to improve services we offer, to improve marketing, analytics, and site functionality. 

**  
b. Personal Information Provided By Users**  
Visitors to our website can register to purchase services. When you register, we will request some personal information such as name, address, email, telephone number or facsimile number, account number and other relevant information. For other types of registrations, we will ask for the relevant information. You may also be asked to disclose personal information to us so that we can provide assistance and information to you. For example, such data may be warranted in order to provide online technical support and troubleshooting. 

We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy statement. We do not sell your personal information to third parties. We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as processing your credit card or offering customer service. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us. 

We may also disclose your personal information  

  * as required by law, such as to to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements, comply with a subpoena, bankruptcy proceedings, or similar legal process 
  * when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request, 
  * if TouchCommerce is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information, 
  * to any other third party with your prior consent to do so. 

**c. Tracking Technologies  
**Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags, scripts or similar technologies are used by TouchCommerce and business partners, affiliates, or analytics or service providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis. 

We use cookies to remember users’ settings (e.g. language preference, last visit). Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited.  **d. Behavioral Advertising  
** We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) (or if located in the European Union click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)) Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads. 

4.

The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as login credentials) on our order forms, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can contact us [here.](http://www.touchcommerce.com/about-us/contact-us)

5\.   
We post customer testimonials/comments/reviews on our web site which may contain personal information. We do obtain the customer's consent via email prior to posting the testimonial to post their name along with their testimonial. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us [here.](http://www.touchcommerce.com/about-us/contact-us) 

6\.   
Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us [here](http://www.touchcommerce.com/about-us/contact-us). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why. 

7\.   
Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. 

8\.   
We use a chat feature to assist you with any questions you may have about our technology and/or services. If our chat feature is offline, please use the “Contact Us” form, we will collect your name and email address so that we may get back to you shortly.  

9\.   
Upon request TouchCommerce will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. 

If your personal information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, amend, delete/remove or deactivate it by making the change on our member information page or by emailing our Customer Support [here](http://www.touchcommerce.com/about-us/contact-us) or by contacting us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below. 

We will respond to your request to access within 2 weeks.   
   
If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter(s), we will use your name and email address to send the newsletter to you. Out of respect for your privacy, you may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails, accessing the email preferences in your account settings page or you can contact us [here](http://www.touchcommerce.com/about-us/contact-us). 

10\.   
We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us [here](http://www.touchcommerce.com/about-us/contact-us). We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

11\.   
The collection and use of information shall be limited to the purpose of providing the service for which the Client has engaged TouchCommerce. If you are a customer of one of our Clients and would no longer like to be contacted by one of our Clients that use our service, please contact the Client that you interact with directly.    
   
**Data Retention:  **TouchCommerce will retain data we process on behalf of our Client for as long as needed provide services to our Client. TouchCommerce will retain and use this personal information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

**Access:  ** TouchCommerce acknowledges that you have the right to access your personal information utilized within the RightTouch system and provides this thru the mechanisms and channels outlined in this disclosure.  As a data processor, TouchCommerce has no direct relationship with the individuals whose data it processes. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data within the RightTouch system should direct his query to the TouchCommerce's Client (the data controller), which has transferred such data to TouchCommerce for processing. If the client requests TouchCommerce to remove the data, TouchCommerce will respond to their Client's request within 30 business days. The Client will then provide access to the individual as determined under the applicable local data protection law.   
   
**Notice:  **As an agent processing information under the direction of its Clients, TouchCommerce has no direct relationship with the individuals whose data it processes. TouchCommerce works with its Clients to help them provide notice of data processing to individuals, including information concerning (1) the purposes for which personal information is collected and used; (2) a contact person to whom enquiries or complaints may be directed; (3) the types of third parties to whom personal information is disclosed; and (4) the choices and means that individuals are offered for limiting use and disclosure of personal information. 

**Choice:  **As an agent processing personal information under the direction of its Clients, TouchCommerce has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. TouchCommerce may disclose personal data to third parties in the course of processing personal data. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the provisions in this Policy regarding notice and choice and the service agreements with our Clients. TouchCommerce only processes information in accordance with instructions of its Clients, and only for purposes that are compatible with those for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized by the individual. TouchCommerce does not process any sensitive data, and only processes personal information that has been collected and provided by its Clients through web or paper-based methods.   
   
12\.   
We may update this privacy statement to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you or our Client by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.    
   
13\.   
If you have questions regarding our Privacy Statement, its implementation, failure to adhere to this Privacy Statement, and/or our general practices, please contact us at: 

**Attention of Privacy/Security Officer**  
29903 Agoura Rd.    
Agoura Hills, California 91301   
818.575.2100 / [info@touchcommerce.com](mailto:info@touchcommerce.com)
